Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we're going to
be purchasing some wine today, right Marco?
That's right. Today we're
going to go to the shop and
we're going to try to
look for some wine that will
go well with the type
of food that we're having.
Alright, so we're going
to be learning a lot
of specific terms. This
is an advanced lesson.
So we expect that most
of the basics you already
know, but some of these
more difficult words and
phrases are going to be our focus.
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
Hello there. Welcome to Wine World.
Let me know if I can help you out at all.
Yes, please. I could
really use some help.
I'm going over to my boss's
house for dinner tonight
and I don't know what
kind of wine I should bring.
Okay. Do you know what
kind of food we'll be served?
Well, his wife is Japanese.
He said she makes really good
sushi. That's a bit of a challenge.
Sushi is notoriously
difficult to pair with wine.
Well, let's see. It'll have to
be a white wine of course.
Why wouldn't a red
wine go well with sushi?
No, I don't think
so. Sushi is a very
delicately flavored food
and red wine would be a
jarring contrast. You need
a white wine which has
more subtle flavors to
complement the fish. I see.
So I should get a
bottle of Chardonnay.
That's a white wine, right?
Yes, Chardonnay is a white
wine, but I'm not sure
it'd be your best bet.
Chardonnay is one of
the more full bodied whites
and tends to be a bit
oaky. I'd suggest you go for
something brighter like this,
Sauvignon Blanc from New Zealand.
Oh, the Sauvignon
Blanc? What's that?
That's another varietal,
or type of grape, just
like Chardonnay. Let's
see. The label says it's got
attractive citrus and
grassy aromas that give way
to crisp mineral flavors
and a bone-dry finish.
Served chilled. Oh,
no. How long will it take
to chill the wine? I'm
on my way to dinner now.
Oh, it's okay. Don't
worry. We'll just choose
a wine from the cooler.
We don't have quite
as extensive a selection over here, but
this Rome Valley white would be lovely.
Alright, what varietal
is that? Well, this is
a French wine, so they
don't always specify the
varietal on the label.
The French believe that
the soil of grape is
grown in is one of the most
important factors in the
final flavor of the wine.
This wine is probably
a blend of a few
different types of grapes,
mostly vignet, I guess.
And you think
this is a good wine?
Yes, this is one of our
best sellers. It's not quite
as dry as the Sauvignon
Blanc we were looking at
earlier, which means
it's more approachable.
It's light and crisp with
a bit of a vanilla aroma.
Perfect. I'll take it.
Alright, we're back. So
now we're talking about
wines and one of the
first things that really
pop up is when we're
talking about sushi and how
we're trying to get a
wine to go well with sushi.
Alright, so the phrase
here was to pair with wine.
So sushi is notoriously
difficult to pair with wine.
Alright, so when you
talk about wine, you
talk about pairing it
with food, P-A-I-R, to pair.
That's right. So for
example, if you're having
meat or poultry or
chicken, you try to pair it
with a wine, so basically that
the flavors go well together.
So commonly we say
that red wine pairs well
with red meat or fish and
white wine pair well together.
So you're pairing these two things
means you're using them in the same meal.
That's right. Okay. So
when we were talking
about pairing a wine
with sushi, the girl said,
well, what about red
wine? Wouldn't that pair
well with sushi? And
the attendant said, no,
the red wine would
be a jarring contrast.
So first of all, we
have this word jarring.
Something is jarring
if it's loud, shocking,
abrasive, difficult,
annoying. So something it's
jarring is loud. And a
contrast is something that
shows the differences
in something. That's right.
So when we're saying
that it would be a jarring
contrast to have sushi with red wine, we're
saying that they're just too different.
Sushi is too different from the red wine
flavor, so they wouldn't go well together.
That's right. And since
jarring means it's a
bad thing, we think the
flavor will be wrong, the bad.
So we need to look
for something else.
And the salesperson
suggested a wine that has
more subtle flavored
white wine. That's right.
So this word subtle is
actually spelled S-U-B-T-L-E,
but the B is
silent. That's right.
So we say subtle. And it's
actually great because it's
kind of like the opposite of jarring.
Something that's not jarring is subtle.
Right. So it's a little bit
more relaxed, not as loud.
It's not obvious.
You have to really
think about it and look
for it. Something that's
subtle is not
obvious. That's right.
Now talking about one specific type
of white wine, we have a chardonnay.
All right. So we
know that there are
many, many different
kinds of wine out there, but
there are some very common
ones. And Chardonnay
is one of those. I think
Chardonnay tends to be a bit fruitier.
Australia has some famous Chardonnay's
California has some famous Chardonnay's.
So just remember that
Chardonnay is a kind of white wine.
That's right. And one of
the ways that they used
it to describe Chardonnay
is that it's one of
the more full bodied
whites. All right.
So whites here, we're talking
about white wines, but something
that's full bodied. What
does that mean, Marco?
So if a wine is full bodied,
it means that it has a
little bit of a stronger flavor, like it's
a more complete flavor. It's not as subtle.
All right. So we know
that white wines are a
bit more subtle than
red wines in this case,
but within white wines,
you can have one that's
very full bodied. So
this is a great phrase for
describing wine. We
don't really talk about other
things being full bodied,
but wine can be full
bodied if it really has
what you say, Marco, this
big full taste of grain
taste. That's right.
And actually, the sales
attendant suggested that,
well, since the Chardonnay
is two or is more full
bodied, then he would
recommend maybe a
Sauvignon Blanc. All
right. So Sauvignon Blanc,
Blanc is the French
word for white, but we use
this all the time in English.
Sauvignon Blanc being
the kind of wine.
Again, it's a white wine.
And it's a bit brighter
than the Chardonnay.
That's what the
salesperson said. That's right.
And when we're talking
about wines, either red wines
or white wines, this, the way to describe
it or the different varieties is actually a
varietal of the wines
or the type of grape.
Right. So varietal, so
you think of varietal,
varietal is a specific
wine word that we use to
describe the kind of
grape that go into a wine.
So we know wine generally
comes from grapes,
they're crushed down and
then the alcohol comes from
all the sugars, but each
different kind of grape
has a different flavor.
And that's the varietal,
the kind of grape.
That's right. So just think
of it as the variety of
the wines that you have,
and it's awards used
specifically for wines.
And well, when the
attendant kept talking about
the wines and the types
of wines they have there,
he mentioned that they have a small selection
in the refrigerator or in the cooler.
So selection in this case means
what the store has to offer.
It means all the wines
that they sell. Right.
So maybe if you have
an extensive selection,
it means you have many, many,
many different kinds to choose from.
But if you don't have an extensive selection,
you have very few wines, that means
that you have fewer
things to sell. That's right.
So a wide selection of wines
or a small selection of wines.
And lastly, talking
about varietals,
we also have what we call a blend, a
blend of a few different types of grapes.
All right. So you can have blends of
different things. But in terms of wine,
we're talking about using
different grapes together
to make one wine. All
right. So this is something
that's pretty common, and it's a way
to achieve different flavors. That's right.
So a blend, you also talk
about it in, I think, whiskies.
You have a blended
whiskies. That's right.
So you can have a single
malt, which is one grain in one
barrel, or you can have
a blend, which would be
different grains fermented
in different barrels
mixed together later.
Okay. So a lot of great stuff
here all about wines. Let's listen
to this dialogue one last time.
Hello there. Welcome to Wine World.
Let me know if I can help you out at all.
Yes, please, I could
really use some help.
I'm going over to my boss's
house for dinner tonight,
and I don't know what
kind of wine I should bring.
Okay. Do you know what
kind of food we'll be served?
Well, his wife is Japanese.
He said she makes
really good sushi. Hmm.
That's a bit of a challenge.
Sushi is notoriously
difficult to pair with wine.
Well, let's see. It'll have to
be a white line, of course.
Why wouldn't the red
wine go out with sushi?
No, I don't think so.
Sushi is a very delicately
flavored food, and red wine
would be a jarring contrast.
You need a white wine, which has more subtle
flavors to complement the fish. I see.
So I should get a bottle of
Chardonnay. That's a white wine, right?
Yes, Chardonnay
is a white wine, but
I'm not sure it'd be your
best bet. Chardonnay is
one of the more full bodied
whites and tends to be a bit oaky.
I'd suggest you go for something
brighter like this, solving your
own blunt from New Zealand.
Oh, the solving your own blunt?
What's that? That's
another varietal or type
of grape, just like
Chardonnay. Let's see.
The label says it's got
attractive citrus and grassy
aromas that give way
to crisp mineral flavors,
and the bone-dried
finish. Served chilled.
Oh, no. How long will
it take to chill the wine?
I'm on my way to
dinner now. Oh, it's okay.
Don't worry. We'll just
choose a wine from the cooler.
We don't have quite as
extensive a selection over
here, but this Rome Valley
white would be lovely.
All right. What varietal
is that? Well, this is
a French wine, so they
don't always specify the
varietal on the label.
The French belief that the
soil of grape is grown in is
one of the most important
factors in the final
flavor of the wine.
This wine is probably a
blend of a few different types
of grapes, mostly vignette,
I guess. And you think
this is a good wine? Yes,
this is one of our best sellers.
It's not quite as dry as the solving
your own blunt we were looking at earlier,
which means it's
more approachable.
It's light and crisp with
a bit of a vanilla aroma.
Perfect. I'll take it.
All right, so obviously
there are a lot more
varietals out there.
We only talked about
two types of wines. We
had a Chardonnay and a
Sauvignon Blanc. That's
right. And the only wines
we talked about were white
wines. Of course, there's
a whole world of
red wines out there.
And then between red and
white, you have rosé, which
are those pink wines.
Those pink wines, yeah.
But actually it's interesting
because the culture
of drinking wine is not as
extensive as we think it is.
In many parts of the world, they're
not really used to drinking wine.
That's right, but then
you go to places like
France and Italy and South
America like Argentina,
Chile, and you experience
these different cultures
of wine that are quite interesting because
they're so different. Yeah, that's right.
And it's become even healthy
to drink wine. A medical test
showed that if you have
one glass of wine with
dinner every day, it reduces
your chances of heart disease.
That's right. There's
some special ingredient.
I'm not sure what it
is, but obviously you
don't want to drink too
much. But if you have a little
bit, it's good for your heart. I think
red wine, they say is good for your heart.
So it's interesting, but obviously
maybe in your countries,
you don't drink wine
or maybe you have a
particular type of wine,
like in China, they have
a, isn't it, plum
wine or rice wine?
Yeah, rice wine in China and
plum wine, I think in Japan.
In Japan. So maybe you
have a specific type of
wine that you want
to let us know about.
And of course, if you have
any questions or comments,
we're always there. Check
us out at www.enguspa.com.
Alright, we'll see you again. Bye.